## **James Charles Funk**

218 South Randall Rd Aurora, IL 60506 · (630) 408-9683 · 1313jcfunk@gmail.com

## **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY:**

I am a committed and resilient individual with a broad range of experience in software development, IT, project management, and collaboration techniques. I have honed my skills in problem-solving, collaboration, compliance, requirement specification, process improvement, application implementation, team building, and project management. My strengths include outstanding organization and self-reliance, excellent communication with all levels of management, and a strong motivation to succeed. I am proficient in using MS Office software and other IT applications in Windows OS.

## **WORK EXPERIENCE:**

GENESIS 10 Milwaukee, WI

Software Developer

September 2021 - November 2022

Created successful programs in Java, SQL, and Javascript along with using REACT API and caching data using HashMap. Achieved the title of Junior Developer upon being contracted to another company after completing a four-month intensive program with minimal coding experience. Code was reviewed and tests were conducted using Spring, and GitHub tools were used for both independent and group projects. Challenges caused by COVID were identified and addressed, resulting in the development of collaborative skills for both remote and on-site assignments. Attended team building exercises and established relationships with fellow coworkers to build a network of connections.

THORNBERRY LTD Lancaster, PA

Junior Software Engineer

February 2022 - October 2022

Developed and managed software that involved the handling of Protected Health Information (PHI) using ObjectScript, SQL, and JavaScript languages. Collaborated with various departments to develop solutions for customers, while working closely with the Lead Developer for final approval of any requested changes. Identified customers' IT needs and provided them with effective solutions. Successful project management was achieved through careful planning, effective communication, and the use of agile methodologies. The software help desk was maintained by providing timely and effective assistance to customers, ensuring that any issues were resolved quickly and to their satisfaction. Collaborative sessions with coworkers were attended and coordinated, fostering an environment of open communication.

## THATCHER TECHNOLOGY GROUP

Naperville, IL

Software Configuration Specialist

May 2023 - March 2024

Assisting both customers and team members to identify possible errors, solutions, and areas for improvement with our software products. Languages used to accomplish tasks include: C#, SQL, Javascript, CSS, along with Powershell scripts. Environments used include: Visual Studio Cron, Visual Studio code, SQL Server Management Studio (SSMS), and Amazon S3. Performed daily interactions with various clients to identify potential work statements to generate and resolve warranty issues. Worked with Project Managers from other departments to ensure tasks were resolved in a collaborative manner. Assisted with the onboard training process of new employees by providing extensive shadowing opportunities. Took active roles in department meetings to help identify what tasks are the highest priority.

**EDUCATION:** 

Lewis University
Bachelor of Education and Elective Studies

**Google IT Certification Course** *Certificate of Completion* 

**Dev10** *Java Full Stack Developer Course* 

Romeoville, IL

*May 2020* 

Online March 2021

Milwaukee, WI December 2021